

Curriculum Vitae
Matthew Degg
3 Beacon Rise
Stone
Staffordshire
ST150AL
07951567940

Matt.degg@outlook.com

Personal Profile

I am a dedicated and enthusiastic professional with nearly 20 years' experience within the construction industry with a strong civils background. I have spent my last 10 years within a supervisory and management role.

I am 100% committed to ensuring that all projects are completed on time and to the highest standard whilst ensuring full compliance with industry regulations relating to health and safety, environment and quality. I am able to work effectively using my own initiative and able to prioritise my workload to achieve challenging deadlines. I possess excellent interpersonal skills enabling me to communicate effectively with stakeholders, clients, colleagues and subcontractors. I enjoy being part of a successful and productive team and thrive in highly pressurised and challenging working environments. I am commercially focused throughout the planning and production stages of all of my projects.

Key skills and Qualities

- Very punctual
- Excellent communication skills
- Strong Leadership Skills
- Work well under pressure
- Safety orientated
- Full UK driving licence
- Strong IT skills
- Work planning/programming
- RAMS Writing and Reviewing
- Commercially Focused
- Knowledge of CDM regulations

Qualifications and Training

- NVQ Level 6 Construction Site Management (QCF)
- NVQ Level 4 Site Supervision
- SMSTS
- 5 Day First Aid
- Temporary Works Supervisor
- Confined Spaces (Medium Risk)
- NVQ level 2 diploma Excavator above and below 10 tonnes
- NVQ Level 2 diploma Telescopic Forklift
- Costain Behavioural Safety
- CSCS Gold Card

Education

Blythe Bridge High School – 2001 Blythe Bridge 6th Form College – 2002

- GCSE English grade c
- GCSE Maths grade c
- GCSE Geography grade c
- GCSE Biology double award grade c,c
- GCSE Physics double award grade c,c
- GCSE Chemistry double award grade c,c
- GCSE Business Studies grade c
- Home Economics grade c
- Computer Literacy and Information Technology. Pass

Work experience

December 2014 - Current - Costain

Minworth Gas to Grid £6m - Site Manager and Civils Package Manager

Development of Health and Safety Management Plan

Responsible for site set up under CDM regulations and ensuring safe environment for all site operatives.

Responsibility and accountability for all site operations and subcontract management.

Responsible for all setting out and management of site engineers.

Implementation of SHE management systems.

Commercial Risk Mitigation.

Ensuring full compliance of Costain's policies and procedures throughout site.

Close Liaison with Client, designers and Contactors including weekly Client meetings and SHEQ reporting.

Carry out weekly SHE and quality audits and close out.

Write, Review and Approve all RAMS associated with the project.

Build and issue detailed scope for issue to Subcontractors for enquiry.

Procure and instruct Subcontractor Packages.

Close detailed management of Civils sub-contractor ensuring any delay to programme is noticed in a timely manner and mitigated where possible.

Capturing Variations to scope and implementation of change management.

Project planning and input to project programme including delivery strategy to ensure key dates are met.

Organisation of Client authorisations for works outside of our CDM area.

Management of snagging works and liaison with client regarding handover.

Management and supervision of all Temporary Works including writing of temporary works briefs for sign off by TWC.

Reporting to Project Manager.

Referee: Steve Czapski, Project Manager

Contact: steve.czapski@costain.com, 07796 373 602

Curdworth Enhanced Monitoring £1.5m – Site Manager

Development of H&S Management Plan

Management of all Civils works including self-delivery and subcontract works.

Management of electrical subcontractors, telemetry upgrade and commissioning.

Leading a team and setting expectations by example.

Behavioural Safety Champion for the project.

RAMS writing, review and approval for all site operations.

Ensuring compliance to Costain's policies and procedures.

Preparation of TBT's and issue to supervisors for briefing.

Development of project programme from start to finish.

Weekly cost reviews and cost reporting.

Close liaison with client and monthly client meetings, reporting progress and programme review.

Implementation of Costain's SHE management systems.

Weekly SHE and quality audits and close outs.

Preparation of client authorisation documentation.

ITP sign offs and quality reporting. Including issue of NCRs and close outs.

Referee: Dave Kellett - Project Manager

Contact: Dave.kellett@costain.com, 07799 435 784

<u>Curdworth Lagoon South Embankment Stabilisation Works - £6m – Site Manager and Multi-Discipline Package</u> <u>Manager</u>

Project Planning and Environmental Risk Mitigation.

Responsible for site set up under CDM regulations and ensuring safe environment for all site operatives.

Review and input to project design.

Development of site H&S Management Plan

Responsibility and accountability for all site operations and subcontract management.

Multi-Discipline package manager.

Management of all self-delivery works.

Crane Supervisor and Co-ordinator.

Behavioural Safety Champion.

Responsible and accountable for prevention of environmental issues including river pollution, existing flora and fauna, flood compensation and lagoon embankment failure.

Close liaison with key stakeholders including Environment Agency and Local Councils.

Development of Project Programme ensuring Key Dates are met.

Responsible for setting out and management of engineers.

Write, Review and Approval of all RAMS.

Weekly progress review and risk mitigation to any delays realised.

Reporting to Project Manager

Referee: Dave Kellett - Project Manager

Contact: Dave.kellett@costain.com, 07799 435 784

A556 Knutsford to Bowden Dual Carriageway Upgrade Scheme - £110m - General Foreman - Civils Package Manager

Management of all Civils Subcontractors.

Management of all self-deliver civils works.

Management of 278 works including planning of required Traffic Management.

Development of self-delivery programmes ensuring works are in line with all subcontract works.

Input to project programme and collaborative planning.

RAMS review and approvals.

Liaison with Stakeholders.

Ensuring compliance of Costain's policies and procedures across site.

Management of SHE management systems.

Logistics and Plant Manager.

Daily SOS briefings and SOS planning meetings.

Night Shift Manager.

ITP sign offs and Quality checks for all civil packages.

Quality audits and reporting.

Reporting to Works Superintendent.

Referee: Mark Malthouse – Works Superintendent Contact: Mark.malthouse@costain.com – 07881 105 746

August 2004 - November 2014 - Laing O'Rourke

North Staffs City General Hospital - £550m - Plant Operative and Self-Deliver Civils Foreman

Day to day management of all self-deliver civils activities.

Development of Self-deliver civils programme ensuring in line with project programme.

Plant and material ordering to ensure work continuity and on time delivery.

Management of site plant to ensure efficient and effective use of on hire plant.

Design change management and capturing variations in scope to allow for material ordering and on time delivery Daily SOS briefings

RAMS briefings and ensuring compliance.

Input to RAMS development to ensure in line with works required and associated methods.

Work planning and delegation to Front Line Supervisors.

Liaising with Site engineers and planning setting out requirements to ensure setting out is carried out in time to suit project programme.

Reporting to Construction Manager.

Referee: Tim Read - Construction Manager

Contact: 077990 774 973

January 2002 – August 2004 – Andy Jack Building Services.

I first started working for AJBS, part time, whilst at school and then again during college. This was where my career prospects took a turn as I enjoyed working with my hands, within a practical role and loved working outdoors.

I worked with a sole trader as a two-man band renovating properties, building extensions, hard and soft land scaping and all aspects of domestic building works.

Whilst working here I learned a lot of the building fundamentals and was able to take the practical knowledge away with me to start my working life within the construction industry.